Emmanouil KARYSTINAIOS



- +30 6973775571
- Vienna, Austria
- manoskary
- in manoskary

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Python, Pytorch, C. OCaml
- Maintenance: Skilled in DevOps practices ensuring continuous integration, testing, and deployment across projects
- Software & Tools : MaxMSP, Reaper, Inkscape, SuperCollider, MuseScore
- Music Instruments : Guitar, Trumpet & Piano
- Music Production: Skilled in composition and audio mixing, with experience producing original music pieces.
- Teaching and Mentorship: Experienced lecturer; supervised many students and interns
- Research Methodology : Published 15+ papers.
- Team Managment : Collaborated in interdisciplinary teams to develop deeplearning models and software for music
- Project Management : Led complex projects, from conception to publication
- Transdisciplinarity: Higher knowledge and degrees from three domains, music, mathematics, and computer science.
- Efficiency and Attention to Detail: Dedicated to efficiency and precision, with a meticulous approach to research, publication, and code quality.
- Adaptability: Worked and lived in 3 countries speaking fluently 4 languages

Language Skills

- French
- English
- \bullet Greek
- German



MIR Research

PROFILE

Emmanouil Karystinaios obtained his Ph.D. in artificial intelligence at the Computational Perception Institute of Johannes Kepler University. His research focuses on , Graph Neural Networks, Computational Musicology and Music Information Retrieval. Currently, he is working on Automatic Analysis of Symbolic Music using Graph Neural Networks (GNNs)

Professional Experience

JOHANNES KEPLER UNIVERSITY

2020 - Present

Conducted Research on Music Information Retrieval and produced over 15 publications in high ranking conferences over the past 3 years.

UNIVERSITY OF MUSIC AND PERFORMING ARTS VIENNA 2022 – 2023 Teaching position as Lecturer on the topic of Music and Sound Computing.

University of Fine Arts Linz

2021 - 2023

Teaching position as Lecturer on the topic of Music and Sound Computing.

Telecom Paris

2019 - 2020

(Internship) Musical style classification with deep learning.

STRASBOURG INSTITUTE FOR ADVANCED MATHEMATICS (Internship) Topological tools for music analysis graphs.

2019

PROJECTS

GRAPHMUSE

2023 - 2024

Created and published an open-source python library for Graph-Based Deep learning on Symbolic music.

- Standardized methodologies for data handling
- Formalized input and output ontologies for graph-based representations of music
- Introduced high-capable music intuitive models

Partitura

2020 - Present

Active developer of the Python package Partitura for symbolic music processing. Main contributions:

- DevOps and continuous development with test suites
- Wrote several parsers for symbolic music formats
- Developed ontologies for musical elements such as harmony, phrases, intervals, etc.

GRAPH MUSIC ANALYSIS

2021 - Present

Developed several State-of-the-art graph-based deep-learning models for music analysis on tasks such as Cadence Detection, Harmonic Analysis, composer classification, and voice separation.

EDUCATION

JOHANNES KEPLER UNIVERSITY LINZ

2021 - 2024

Doctorate Degree on AI from the Department of Technical Sciences.

DIDEROT UNIVERSITY PARIS 7

2018 - 2020

Master on Mathematical Logic and Programming Fundamentals from the Department of Mathematics

DESCARTES UNIVERSITY PARIS 8

2017 - 2019

Master of Composition and Musical Programming from the Department of Fine Arts

Aristotle University of Thessaloniki

2012 - 2017

Diploma of Musicology from the Department of Fine Arts with integrated Master on Composition and Analysis